Tauseef Ibne Mamun

tmamun@mtu.edu +1 (857)-574-9931 https://tmamun.netlify.app

407 Shelden Avenue, Apt 9, Houghton, Michigan, 49931

SUMMARY

Ph.D. student with specialized training in both *human-computer interaction* and *behavioral psychology*. Have a *strong programming* background. Experience in advanced-level human factors engineering (*qualitative* and *quantitative*) and executing *usability* studies mainly in software and rail warning systems.

Research Tools/Methods

- Behavioral studies with human subjects
- Usability Evaluation in both real-time and simulated environments (eye-tracking, driving simulator, in-vehicle systems, healthcare systems)
- Cognitive Task Analysis (CTA)
- Computational modeling
- Software development
- Development of R libraries for data management and interpretation

EXPERIENCES

Michigan Technological University, Cognitive and Learning Sciences | Houghton, MI

Research Assistant 2019 – Present

Tasks:

- User behavior analysis in autonomous driving for user-centric explanations.
- Designing novel explanation methods for the human-AI teaming.
- Developing computational models for naturalistic decision-making scenarios.
- Behavioral analysis of drivers in rail crossings through mixed-method approach.
- Assessment of the usability of new in-vehicle systems in rail crossings.
 - Working/Worked with Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency and Federal Railroad Administration on different research projects.

Mighty Egg Technologies | Canada/Bangladesh

Programmer Analyst

2015 - 2018

Tasks:

- Database Design & API development.
- Web and Mobile App Development.

Software deployment in Amazon Web Service, Digital Ocean, Heroku.

Programming Expertise

R, Python, C, C++, Java, PHP, Ruby, PEBL (*Git*: <u>GitHub</u> (https://github.com/tm012)

EDUCATION

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

Ph.D. Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors

Expected 2023

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

Artificial Intelligence in Healthcare Certificate

2021

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

MS Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors

2019 - 2021

Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology | Dhaka, Bangladesh

BS Computer Science & Engineering

2011 - 2015

FEATURED LEADERSHIP ROLES

- Vice President at Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology's Computer Science & Engineering Society 2014 –
 2015
- Vice President at Bangladeshi Student Association at Michigan Technological University

2020 - 2021

INTERESTS